GHEORGHE CRACIUN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mobile: 07927769866 <u>GitHub</u>

Address: Flat 118, Abacus Building, 246 Bradford Street, Birmingham B12 0NZ

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Email: gheorghecr1997@gmail.com

Portfolio

PERSONAL PROFILE

A Computer Science graduate from Coventry University with proven experience in developing software and web applications. Known as a proactive self-starter, quick learner with solid problem-solving skills that is highly interested in Software Development. Able to collaborate with others but also able to work independently to achieve objectives on time and with excellence. Passionate about developing new skills and keeping up to date with current technologies.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Most Experienced with Flutter, Dart, Python, Django, Swift, SwiftUI, Java
- Some Experience with JavaScript, TypeScript, Firebase, Azure, Angular, Node.JS, HTML5
- Beginner with React, CSS, Koa, PHP
- Professional experience using Agile methodology, Git, GitHub and Unit Testing
- Experience with as SQL and NoSQL databases
- Familiarity of XCode, Android Studio, Visual Studio and IntelliJ IDEA

OTHER SKILLS

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design, and implement database structures
- Detail-oriented
- Excellent problem solver with great decision-making skills
- Effective time management skills and ability to work under pressure

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EriccTS Ltd - Birmingham, UK | July 2020 - Present

- Build and maintain a performant API system that serves the customer-facing console frontend using Django
- Participated and contributed to the full development life cycle, including planning, analysis, design, implementation and maintenance
- Helped to develop the frontend application using Flutter

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST

EriccTS Ltd - Birmingham, UK | July 2019 - July 2020

- Data analysis in order to help stores to improve energy consumption, leading to a 10% energy saving during a twelve-month period
- Prepared detailed energy reports to be evaluated at the headquarters
- iOS application engineering for a big multi-national retailer using SWIFT
- Java/JavaFX touchscreen desktop application development & maintenance for a big multi-national retailer

PROGRAM TECHNICIAN

Pahldata - Lisbon, Portugal | May - July 2015 & January - March 2016

- Repaired and configured communication equipment using C programming language
- Delivered and installed communication equipment
- Participated in teaching sessions about programming routers using C as the programming language

RESTAURANT SUPERVISOR

Days Hotel - Coventry, UK | August 2017 - July 2018

- Trained new and current employees on the use of ICR TOUCH till software
- Handled customer inquires and complaints about service and food quality
- Improved stock management trough while utilising excellent organisational and problem-solving skills which reduced the restaurant waste

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- Portuguese Native
- Romanian Native
- Spanish Intermediate

EDUCATION HISTORY

BSC (HONS) COMPUTER SCIENCE

Coventry University - Coventry, UK | September 2017 - May 2021

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

IOS & ANDROID MOBILE GAME - MUZZI (SIDE PROJECT)

- The application is a Party Game that focuses on finding more about our friends or family and getting everyone together through music
- Used Flutter for the development of the application
- Team Member
- Responsible for the planning, development and testing of the application
- Worked with RESTful API's, Firebase
- Experienced with Apple App Store Guidelines
- Experienced with App Store Connect
- Available on App Store and Play Store

ERICCTS APP - IOS APPLICATION

- Sole Developer
- Designed, developed, and tested the EriccTS application for iOS/macOS devices using Swift 5
- Understanding of UIKit, Cocoa Touch, Cocoa Pods, Core Animation, Networking, Core Data, Storyboards
- Working on agile scrum methodology and involving in a stand-up meeting to monitor the progress
- Experienced with MVC design patterns and Unit Tests with XCTest
- Worked with RESTful Web Services using URLSession
- Applied TCP Connections between the backend server and the application
- An in-app messaging system built from scratch
- Successfully launched the application to the APP Store, only available internally

ERICCTS JAVA/JAVAFX - DESKTOP APPLICATION

- Team Member
- Designed, developed, and tested a touchscreen application
- · Working on agile scrum methodology and participated in stand-up meetings to monitor the progress
- Applied TCP Connections
- Applied MVC design pattern

INTERESTS



Tech



Reading



Tennis



Portuguese Society at Coventry University



Travelling



-utsa